- Giddy up!
Xiang!
Let go of me!
- You two wenches.
- Let go!
Just yield!
If you run again, I'll kill Xiang!
Ting Hui!
Xiang!
I'll kill you!
[Episode 1]
Giddy up!
[Shazhou]
Young master, Shazhou ahead.
According to our secret guards,
this strategic military stronghold
is involved in the illegal arms trade.
And Governor Ding Chong is behind it.
He is the prized follower of Lord Xu.
Before the fasting period ends,
we must determine
how involved Xu Ting is in this
and return to the capital with the evidence.
As you command.
- Giddy up!
Giddy up!
It's Huo An.
It seems Lord Xu doesn't want me,
the emperor, to continue the investigation.
Young master, I'll deal with them.
Stick to the plan. Split up.
Huo An.
You'll have to get past me first.
Charge!
[Shazhou]
Hot steamed buns!
[Shazhou Women's Academy]
Predictions for the women's Provincial Exam.
The only one in all of Shazhou.
First come, first served.
Meng Ting Hui, how much is it this time?
The starting price is 30 taels.
- 30 taels!
Last month's academy exam predictions
were only ten taels!
It's for the Provincial Exam this time!
Women haven't been allowed
to take the imperial exam for nine years.
Finally, His Majesty
has reopened the Imperial Exam.
Once you pass, you'll serve His Majesty
and rise to fame and fortune.
It's not even expensive
to sell it at 1,000 taels.
You hit three essay questions
for last month's academy exam.
I'll buy it this time.
I'll pay 35 taels.
Last time, I was at the top of the academy
thanks to her questions.
I'll pay 40 taels.
I'll pay 45 taels.
- 50 taels!
- Sold!
Let me see who dares to buy!
Jiang Mei Er.
- Are you nuts?
- Don't be impulsive.
Listen, last month,
Wen just talked back to her once
and was then expelled from the academy.
My uncle is the Governor of Shazhou.
He funds this academy.
If you offend me,
none of you will have a place in Shazhou.
What does my business have to do with you?
Meng Ting Hui, if it weren't
for you selling predictions every month,
how could I always be last?
You can be a buyer too.
My uncle has ruled
that girls pay 100 taels
to register for the Imperial Exam.
You're just a poor orphaned girl.
You can't marry into a wealthy family
or run a profitable business.
Now you're dreaming of changing your life
through the Imperial Exam.
You wish!
You rely on your family,
and I rely on my ability.
Whether I can do it, let's see on the exam!
[Personal Dossier: identity certificate]
If your dossier gets blown away by the wind,
can you take the imperial exam then?
How dare you! How did you get my dossier?
My uncle is the Governor of Shazhou.
You always talk about your uncle.
You're not tired of saying it,
but we're tired of hearing it.
Stop laughing!
Meng Ting Hui, considering we are classmates,
if you kneel down and sincerely beg me,
I might just be merciful
and return your dossier.
Kneel right away.
Otherwise, you'll miss the chance.
Since you insist, you kneel for me!
How dare you!
Jiang Mei Er, return my dossier!
Shazhou is just a tiny place.
Just wait. You'll be punished by the law.
And I'll tear apart your arrogant faces.
But what can you do to me now?
People are born different from each other.
My uncle holds power in Shazhou.
So, what can you do to me?
I'll fight you with my life!
Meng Ting Hui, you're crazy!
If you don't want your face ruined,
return my dossier!
Return my dossier!
Xia, give it back to her! Hurry!
Meng Ting Hui, you're crazy!
Meng Ting Hui wants to kill me!
[Personal Dossier Holder: Meng Ting Hui]
You two brats!
I raised you,
fed you,
and taught you skills.
Yet you try to run away!
You forced us to steal and cheat.
You never taught us.
You treated us like animals.
You never raised us.
Without me, you would have starved to death.
I'm not afraid of death.
But we want to see you die!
If one day I have a knife in my hand,
I'll cut you into pieces!
Is this how you repay your lifesaver?
You don't deserve my repayment!
You abduct women, traffic children,
and kill at will.
You are a heinous criminal!
I'm a criminal?
Show me your evidence. What charges?
Who will convict me?
Just you?
Who would believe a little beggar like you?
The officials all consider me a good citizen.
But you, a little liar,
want to kill me?
You are
just a murderer!
Meng!
I heard
Jiang Mei Er came picking on you again.
She really thinks we're easy to bully!
I failed the academy exam anyway,
so I'm not afraid of being expelled.
Look, I'll smash her
with my abacus right now.
Come back!
You mustn't do that!
This abacus is what your mother left you.
It's not worth using it to hit her.
Jiang Mei Er did this?
You need to write with this hand!
I'm going to tear her apart right now!
Come back!
How could she get the better of me?
I snatched her dagger
and almost slit her throat.
You didn't see
how she was scared out of her wits
and fled in panic.
Have a seat.
You promised me
you would focus on studying
and not confront her head-on.
I had no choice this time.
She threatened me with my dossier.
Here it is. I snatched it back!
Ever since I met you,
[Shuxiu: students' payment to teachers]
you've been doing odd jobs for your tuition
and studying late into the night.
I know
you've been hoping to take the imperial exam.
But in my opinion,
nothing is worth risking your life.
I might be an orphan girl, but I'm tough.
Anyway, Jiang Mei Er is a vengeful girl.
You can't stay in this dormitory.
Pack your things and stay at my place.
Fu Zhi.
I shouldn't go.
Every time I go to your house,
your stepmother looks at me like I'm a thief.
How about moving to Bofeng?
So, your father and stepmother agreed
to let you run Bofeng?
Father becomes a stepfather
once he remarries.
My stepmother is unhappy
about me failing the academy exam,
so she handed over the dying Bofeng to me.
She even said
if I can't earn 300 taels within a month,
I'll have to obediently get married.
But are women born to be housewives?
I may not be good at studying,
but I'm good with the abacus.
I'm also good at doing business.
Yet they just look down on me.
Fu Zhi.
Let's go make our fortune in the capital.
You open a restaurant,
and I'll pursue an official career.
In the capital,
we will surely make it.
Good idea!
But right now,
they're deliberately forcing me to marry.
It's been bothering me.
I'll help you figure something out.
Really?
Then you save up for the registration fee.
Let's earn money together
and turn the corner.
Sure, let's turn the corner.
Situ Xue.
Situ Xue is here!
Who is Situ Xue?
She is the top dancer in the capital.
Whatever she eats or uses becomes popular.
Yes, His Majesty praised her
when she performed at the Flower Festival.
Situ Xue!
I got it! Situ Xue!
Everyone gets one. Come on.
Today, Situ Xue will dance at Bofeng.
The Spring-Autumn Pastry
made by Miss Situ is 20 percent off.
Everyone, hurry to Bofeng to see Situ Xue!
Situ Xue!
Honored guests, today, Bofeng reopens.
We've specially invited Situ Xue,
the top dancer, to perform here.
Great!
All guests
can watch Miss Situ's dancing up close.
For three days only!
- Great!
Please welcome Miss Situ!
[Coffin of Madam Wang, Mother of Feng Lu]
Mr. Feng's mother has passed away.
Voluntary mourning.
Put it on!
Mr. Feng's mother has passed away.
Voluntary mourning.
[Memorial Tablet of Madam Wang,
Mother of Feng Lu]
[Feng Lu, Head of the Heihu Crew]
[Wedding Convoy]
[Coffin of Madam Wang, Mother of Feng Lu]
Let's talk this over.
Get down!
Come out!
My dear!
Go away!
It's my wedding day.
[Coffin of Madam Wang, Mother of Feng Lu]
How can I wear mourning clothes?
Just shut up!
My dear!
[Bofeng]
Bofeng is finally going to come back to life!
We paid a lot for the camels
and parade float, and it all paid off.
Great!
[Zhang's Lamb Soup]
Today is my mother's funeral.
And yet
someone dares to open for business!
Men!
The Heihu Crew is here! Run!
The Heihu Crew is holding a funeral.
Quick, close the business
and send the guests away.
Mr. Feng's mother has passed away.
Yet you're dressed so gaudily,
deliberately going against the Heihu Crew!
Please calm down.
We'll change into mourning clothes right away
to express our condolences.
You've offended the old madam's death day!
We'll turn your celebration into a funeral!
I am the boss of Bofeng.
She is just my honored guest.
If you have any issues, come at me!
I'll grant your wish!
Playing the hero?
Guess who stands behind the Heihu Crew?
Governor Ding Chong, the ruler of Shazhou!
They have many people and power.
We can't afford to offend them.
Don't worry. You don't need to fear them.
Very bold of you, young master.
It's fine if you're not afraid,
but don't drag Bofeng into this.
How dare you!
Local military weapon?
How do you have a military knife?
If you like it, I'll give it to you.
This person arrogantly provokes you,
but he has nothing to do with Bofeng.
Fu Zhi.
Meng.
We already offended them on opening day.
What will happen to future business?
Don't worry.
The guy out there is fighting them.
He doesn't look like a local,
so maybe he can handle it.
Fu Zhi, you leave through the back door
and go home.
Take a break for now.
No, you did this to help me.
How could I abandon you?
They don't even know what I look like.
If your father hears about today from others,
he will blame you.
You'd better go home now and explain to him
in case your stepmother
makes a fuss about it.
You hide on the second floor.
I'll come find you tomorrow.
- Okay.
Young master,
we've closed the business for today.
Please leave.
You've trespassed into a woman's room.
If you don't leave now, I'll call for help.
Go.
Where did you get this dagger?
I picked it up on the road.
It's specially made by the Shazhou Armory.
You sure picked up good stuff.
I'm just a commoner.
How would I recognize such military items?
But how come you are so familiar with it?
Could you be a deserter?
Are the people out there hunting you?
Just now, you used me to get away.
How could you repay kindness with enmity?
Please leave immediately,
and don't pester me anymore.
You impersonated Situ Xue
to deceive the people.
You hold a military weapon
with ill intentions.
By law, you should be exiled.
What makes you say I'm fake?
That's because I met the real Situ Xue once.
Help!
Stop!
Did you sleep well?
Return my dossier.
Where did the weapon come from?
It's from Jiang Mei Er.
Go on.
Her uncle is Ding Chong,
the Governor of Shazhou.
I accidentally took it
during a fight with her at the academy.
The Heihu Crew acts lawlessly in Shazhou.
And Ding Chong sit secure
on his position as Governor of Shazhou.
The Heihu Crew acts as his henchmen.
For years,
they've seized fertile land for him,
forced women into prostitution,
and murdered merchants.
Their crimes are numerous.
Shazhou borders Beijian.
It's a strategic military location,
but it's far from the emperor's reach.
With the garrison stationed here,
no one manages Shazhou's affairs.
In Shazhou, Ding Chong is the emperor.
Is there a black market in Shazhou?
In Jiuyou City,
you can buy all kinds of forbidden goods.
As long as you can afford the price,
there's nothing they dare not sell.
Where is it?
Go south three li from Bofeng,
and you'll see a poplar forest.
Then follow the riverbed east, and you'll...
Young master, the local terrain is complex.
Release me, and I'll draw you a detailed map.
In that case,
I'll trouble you to lead the way personally.
Even if I'm to lead the way,
you have to release me first.
After all, I'm just a weak woman.
Don't play tricks.
Until I find out the truth about the weapon,
you can't go anywhere.
We're going to Jiuyou City now.
It's too late.
Jiuyou City opens at the hour of You
and closes at the hour of Zi.
We'll have to wait until tomorrow night.
You are selfish and full of lies.
After being exposed, you tried to quibble.
You can easily play innocent and pitiful.
So you're quite cunning,
deceitful, and two-faced.
How do I know you're not lying to me?
You really have a deep impression of me.
I can take you
to the entrance of Jiuyou City.
But please allow me
to leave immediately afterwards.
Fu Zhi's restaurant just opened.
I also need to prepare for the imperial exam.
We just want to find a way to survive.
We don't dare
go to the terrifying Jiuyou City,
let alone get involved
with weapons and Ding Chong.
That sounds more believable.
You were so anxious about this dossier.
Are you trying to become an official?
None of your business!
That's the only path
I can take.
[Tomb of Xiang]
Xiang.
From now on, I'm alone. What should I do?
Xiang
would surely want you to live on bravely.
I want to avenge Xiang's death!
I'll make those villains suffer
a million times more than her!
Hatred only blinds people,
making them unable to see the path ahead.
There are many ways to seek justice.
Becoming strong is the best way
to take revenge.
How can I become as strong as you?
Go study, pass the imperial exam,
and become an official.
When you hold power,
everything will be different.
The women's imperial exam
has been suspended three times.
This year,
the Imperial Exam is held for the first time.
But the court demands 100 taels
for its registration.
Many local women are deterred by the money.
I still haven't saved enough money.
Only by becoming an official
can one have power.
This dossier is my life.
Absurd!
The court never charged registration fees.
In Shazhou,
Ding Chong's rules are the court's rules.
The imperial exam is imminent.
I'm just protecting myself.
What's wrong with that?
Sounds reasonable and convincing.
However, it's hard to tell if you're lying.
I'll return your dossier
once we reach Jiuyou City.
♪ Please drink one more cup of wine ♪
[Ding Chong, Governor of Shazhou]
♪ No old friends outside the pass ♪
Mr. Ding.
Your sister, Mrs. Jiang,
has sent the profit share and the guest list.
Here are also the accounts of Jiuyou City.
His black market business
is a capital offense.
Tell Feng Lu to sell secretly next time
and have his minions keep a low profile.
It's too conspicuous.
Mr. Feng has you as his backer,
so he's grown ever more bold.
Today, his mother passed away.
They even forced people to wear mourning.
They not only hacked a groom to death,
but also injured many people.
That idiot always causes trouble for me!
Mr. Feng knows he's troubling you,
so he decided to give you more.
That's considerate.
[Guest List of the Silver House]
Uncle!
Be careful.
Uncle, did Yan Fu Zhi give you any money
when she opened her restaurant?
What money?
Sir,
Miss Yan took over Bofeng
and reopened it today.
She invited Situ Xue from the Huiyin House
in the capital to build up hype.
It's said she is the top dancer there
and a peerless beauty.
Tell me, who is more beautiful,
me or Situ Xue?
Of course, Situ Xue.
No, you're more beautiful,
radiant, and charming.
Situ Xue is just a performer.
How can she compare to you?
Uncle.
Yan Fu Zhi doesn't take you seriously.
She didn't even invite you to her opening.
And she even helped Meng Ting Hui fight me.
Uncle, look!
Meng Ting Hui even hurt my neck.
They almost killed me!
So Uncle, you must teach them a lesson.
Last time in the academy exam,
because Meng Ting Hui
sold the exam questions in advance,
I ended up with the lowest rank.
Don't you feel embarrassed?
Without me, you wouldn't
even have made the bottom of the list.
I've already paved the path
for your exam in the capital.
But you still have to study,
even just for show.
That's the important thing.
Don't keep fighting against an orphan girl.
Got it, Uncle.
And I'll arrange a decent, easy job
for you then.
Will you take it?
Of course, thank you, Uncle!
I knew you are the best
and would definitely have my back.
Wait.
Isn't this jewelry from last month?
Come on.
Take this and buy new jewelry.
Thank you, Uncle. I'll go now.
Study hard, and don't end up last again!
Got it.
She is kind of goofy,
just like her short-lived father.
She has a pretty face but no brains.
By the way, has the registration fee
for the Imperial Examination been collected?
[Xu Ting, Left Chancellor]
Lord Xu.
It's already very late,
but you're still working.
And our new emperor used his seclusion
to sneak out of the palace.
It's quite inappropriate.
[Memorial from Magistrate Wang Song Ping]
Young people enjoy traveling.
But I never thought
[Memorial from Minister Wan Kai]
he'd allow women to take the imperial exam.
He didn't learn enough lessons
from the previous abolition of women's exams.
Women can't be involved in politics,
or the state will surely be in a crisis.
Their political participation
is absolutely unacceptable.
I agree, my lord.
Women may not even have read
The Nine Chapters on the Mathematical Art.
How can they involve themselves
in state affairs?
As for His Majesty,
under the pretext of seclusion,
he secretly visited Shazhou.
Did he act on impulse?
Or is he up to something?
Anyway, he's still too young.
No need to worry.
I've had Huo An go to Shazhou
and bring His Majesty back.
Otherwise, on the day of emergence,
our national dignity will be endangered.
Meng, wake up quickly!
Meng, get dressed right now!
Many guests have come, all here for Situ Xue.
We're going to be rich!
Meng, you really are my lucky star!
You audacious lecher,
how dare you barge into Meng's room!
Meng, did he touch you?
Are you okay?
Fu Zhi.
You lecher, I'll kill you right now!
I'll chop you to pieces!
As expected of this place.
The locals are indeed fierce.
You mean I'm fierce? Prepare to die!
Fu Zhi, he didn't take liberties with me.
Then who is he?
Why is he in your room early in the morning?
Yesterday in front of Bofeng,
it was he who came to our rescue.
I feared he'd be hunted by the Heihu Crew,
so I let him take shelter here.
So you saved our lives.
Forgive me, young master.
Yesterday, I left in a hurry
and didn't see you clearly.
You are handsome,
an elegantly dressed gentleman,
with an extraordinary bearing!
Fu Zhi, he knows I'm not Situ Xue.
You saved us, but you can't be alive!
Meng pretended to be Situ Xue for my sake.
And I'm the boss of Bofeng.
Since you already know our secret,
you can't live. Prepare to die!
No wonder you're good friends.
You have the same temper.
Meng!
You want to make money
by impersonating Situ Xue, right?
Let me teach Miss Meng
how to do it more convincingly.
Situ Xue was born in March
and loves crabapple blossoms.
With this crabapple flower,
Miss Meng will be Situ Xue.
I didn't expect you to know Situ Xue.
What a pleasant surprise!
You two can be friends.
- No way!
But friends also settle accounts clearly.
Yesterday's lodging fee,
today's get-scared fee,
wall repair fee,
- and medical expenses...
- Both hands.
Altogether,
three times the room rate, payable in cash.
Young master,
are you trying to skip out on the bill?
The jade is translucent
and warms to the touch.
Good jade.
How should I address you, young master?
He Du.
I'll leave this jade pendant
as collateral with you for now.
Once my friend arrives,
I'll pay the full amount.
Alright, good.
With this jade pendant, you can stay forever.
No, I'm taking you away today.
If there's nothing else, you may leave now.
Sure.
Fu Zhi, he must be sent away.
For the sake of the jade pendant,
just let it go.
His pendant is worth
at least ten houses in Shazhou.
He doesn't seem ordinary and is so showy.
Sooner or later,
he'll bring trouble to Bofeng. He must leave.
I also need to get my dossier back.
Your dossier?
Come take a look.
Miss Meng, these are newly acquired books.
I saved them especially for you.
Thank you, sir.
You're welcome. Come again.
Black leather boots,
belt for military officers,
and long sword.
They must be military officers
from the capital.
Find him! Check every corner!
Search!
Sir, look!
[I saw this person at Guxiang Street
at the hour of Chen]
Move!
Mr. He, we need to hurry,
or we'll miss the opening of Jiuyou City.
Meng Ting Hui.
Where did you hook another rich young master?
Good for you.
No man wants an orphan girl,
yet you actually landed a rich man.
Not everyone relies on marriage
to change their fate like you.
You want to change it, but you can't, right?
I heard you offended Jiang Mei Er.
Just give up on the Imperial Examination now.
All these years, you've been deceiving Fu Zhi
to get free food and shelter from our family.
Otherwise,
you'd have ended up in the streets.
Mrs. Yan, watch your words.
I work and study at the women's academy.
I've never taken advantage of the Yan family.
Unlike you, Mrs. Yan.
Nice silk
and jewels.
The Yan family's accounts
probably can't withstand a close inspection.
You can turn black into white.
You've been surviving by deception
since childhood.
And you're always scheming.
No wonder Fu Zhi treats you so well.
Mr. Yan, you're here.
My dear!
My dear.
You say I'm good at scheming?
Your ability to change faces
is even more brilliant.
Young master,
you have an extraordinary bearing.
Just a reminder for you.
Stay away from this bad girl.
She will kill for money.
When I was pregnant,
she pushed me down the stairs.
She is quite vicious for a young girl.
It's not too late to leave now.
Miss Meng,
you're getting more and more interesting.
Aren't we going to Jiuyou City?
I already gave you a chance.
If you're not leaving, then sorry.
Meng Ting Hui really surprised me.
She even gathered all of you together.
[Bingjianzi: meaning friends, brothers]
Bingjianzi, where are you from?
Let's not mistake each other.
This guy is not easy to deal with.
Let's cooperate and take out his legs.
- Spare me, sir!
- We won't do it again!
We won't do it again! Spare us!
- Spare me, sir!
Where did you get this military knife?